pamgolding.co.za 2019-07-14

# Privacy Policy | Pam Golding Properties

We are committed to **ensuring that your privacy is protected**. Below, we’ve outlined the procedures we have in place to safeguard your privacy, ways we use the information we collect as well as ways to limit the use of this information **according to your preferences**.

## Pam Golding Group Website Privacy Policy

  1. **Introduction**
    1. This Website Privacy Policy (" **Privacy Policy** ") is provided by PGP (as defined under the **Terms and Conditions**) and pertains to the personal information which PGP may from time to time collect from you when you access and/or use the Website ([www.pamgolding.co.za](http://www.pamgolding.co.za/)).
    2. PGP is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. This Privacy Policy explains how we use personal information we collect about you and how you can instruct us if you prefer to limit the use of that information. 
    3. In this Privacy Policy the term " _third parties_ " means persons, firms or companies which are not subsidiaries of or otherwise associated with PGP.
  2. **The information we collect**
    1. Whilst using the Website, PGP may electronically collect, store and use certain " _personal information_ " about you as is set out in this Privacy Policy. The term " ** _personal information_** " shall bear the same meaning under this Privacy Policy as defined in the Protection of Personal Information Act, 4 of 2013. 
    2. In using and/or accessing the Website you may provide us with (or we may, from time to time, require you to provide us with) certain " _personal information_ " which may include, but is not limited to, information pertaining to your:
      1. name and surname;
      2. email address; and
      3. mobile number.
  3. **Cookies**
    1. The Website uses "cookies" or similar technology through which we may automatically collect personal information about you (being your name, surname, email address and mobile number). "Cookies" will further be used to record the properties that you have browsed. We collect this information in order that we may show those properties to you again and provide you with recommendations based on your search criteria. Please see the terms and conditions applicable to " ** _Cookies_** " under our **Terms and Conditions**. ****
    2. **You can set your browser to notify you when you are sent a "Cookie", giving you the chance to decide whether or not to accept it.**   If you accept a "cookie" or fail to deny the use of "cookies", you consent to our use of your personal information collected using "cookies" (subject to the provisions of this Privacy Policy and the Terms and Conditions).
    3. The Website also utilises remarketing (or similar audiences) in Google AdWords, allowing us to show ads to users who have previously visited the Website as they browse the Web. In other words, if you visit our Website and then visit another unrelated website, an ad for our Website may be shown on that site. Through this we are able to present you with highly relevant advertisements and offers across the Web.
    4. The remarketing tag is placed across all non-sensitive pages on our Website. When you visit different pages, your "cookie" identity is added to the remarketing list.
    5. If you do not accept Google's use of "cookies" you can opt out of Google's use of "cookies" by visiting Google's Ads Settings by clicking on: <http://www.google.com/settings/ads>.  Alternatively you can opt out of a third-party's use of cookies by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page by clicking on: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>.
  4. **Social media**
    1. If you share our Website or Website Content (as defined under the **_Terms and Conditions_** ) on any social media (such as Facebook or Twitter) your personal information (e.g. your name and the fact that you are interested in anything advertised or displayed on the Website) will be visible to all the visitors of your personal webpage on Facebook and/or Twitter. 
    2. **When you use social media websites the terms and conditions (including the privacy policy/ies) of such social media website/s will apply to you.**
    3. **PGP is not responsible for the processing of personal information or the privacy policy/ies of such social media website/s. This Privacy Policy is therefore not applicable to such social media website/s.**
    4. **If you disclose your personal information to a third party such as Facebook or Twitter, PGP will not be liable for any loss or damage, howsoever arising (whether direct, indirect or consequential), suffered by you as a result of the disclosure of your personal information to such third parties. This is because PGP do not regulate or control how such third parties use your personal information. You should always ensure that you read and understand the privacy policies of such third parties / social media website/s.**
  5. **Our Facebook page**
    1. We have a Facebook page. When you communicate with us through our Facebook page (for example, when you post a comment, upload media, send a personal message or become a fan of us by clicking the " _Like_ " button) we may receive personal information about you (such as your (user) name, profile photo, your hometown, your email address and/or your gender). The manner in which your personal information is used will be described in the applicable Facebook privacy policy. You should read the Facebook privacy policy together with this Privacy Policy and the terms of use and/or other privacy statements on Facebook. 
    2. PGP encourages you to carefully read the Facebook privacy policy, terms of use and other privacy statements on Facebook which may differ from this Privacy Policy.
  6. **How we use your personal information**
    1. PGP will only use your personal information to compile the Website, provide you with information, communicate with you, respond to enquiries made by you, manage our relationship with you and provide services or marketing material to you, including alerts on new [property for sale](https://www.pamgolding.co.za/buy-property) or [rent ](https://www.pamgolding.co.za/rent-property)matching your search criteria (where you have opted to receive such material or submitted your details to receive regular information from us via email).
    2. Further to the above, by using the Website, you consent to PGP using or disclosing your personal information for purposes of:
      1. statistical and/or data analysis; 
      2. processing any contact, communication or transaction which you have initiated, requested or otherwise indicated an interest in; 
      3. the ordinary course of PGP's business; and
      4. promotion and marketing.
    3. We or our agents and/or sub-contractors may contact you by post, email or telephone from time to time to ask you for your feedback and comments on our services. **On each occasion you will be provided with the option to "opt-out"**.
    4. PGP will not disclose your personal information to anyone except as provided for in this Privacy Policy. We may, however, need to disclose your personal information to PGP employees, agents and/or third party service providers  who require such information to carry out their duties or otherwise in instances where this is pursuant to a contact, communication or transaction that you have initiated or requested. 
    5. Your personal information may, in the ordinary course of business, move between different companies or business units in PGP. This may involve the transfer of your personal information outside the borders of South Africa, provided that the disclosure of your personal information shall be in accordance with the purpose for which the personal information was collected from you. There may also be situations where the law requires us to disclose your personal information. In all other situations, PGP will not disclose your personal information without giving you prior notice thereof and an opportunity to give your consent thereto where required.
    6. PGP will not use your personal information for any purpose (other than as stated above) without your consent. 
  7. **Sale of business**
    1. In the event that PGP's business is sold or integrated with another business your personal information may be disclosed to our advisers and any prospective purchaser and their advisers and will be passed on to the new owners of the business. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to notify you (by posting on the Website or via an email sent to your email address provided to us) of any such change.
  8. **How do we protect your personal information**
    1. You acknowledge that the Internet is not a secure medium; however, we have put in place various security measures to protect your personal information. 
    2. PGP takes security and privacy of your personal information seriously and we have internal procedures in place which cover storage, access and disclosure of your personal information.
    3. We will ensure that all PGP employees, agents and/or third party service providers having access to your personal information are bound by appropriate confidentiality and non-use obligations in relation to your personal information.
  9. **Our commitment**
    1. PGP will- 
      1. treat your personal information as strictly confidential;
      2. take certain technical and organisational measures to protect your personal information;
      3. provide you with reasonable access to your personal information on the Website to view and/or update personal details;
      4. as soon as reasonably possible after the discovery of a compromise, and insofar as we can establish your identity, notify you that there are reasonable grounds to believe that your personal information has been accessed or acquired by an unauthorised person; and
      5. upon your reasonable written request, return or destroy any and all of your personal information which may be in our possession or control.
    2. **Whilst PGP will do all things reasonably necessary to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee nor do we accept any liability of whatsoever nature for any unauthorised or unlawful disclosure and/or use of your personal information, either by employees and/or agents and/or made by third parties (including third party service providers) who are not subject to our control, unless such disclosure and/or use is as a result of our gross negligence.**
    3. If you disclose your personal information to any third party (including an entity which operates a website linked to the Website) other than PGP, **PGP SHALL NOT BE LIABLE FOR ANY LOSS OR DAMAGE, HOWSOEVER ARISING, SUFFERED BY YOU AS A RESULT OF THE DISCLOSURE OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION TO SUCH THIRD PARTIES**. This is because PGP do not regulate or control how third parties use your personal information. You should always ensure that you read the privacy policy of any third party that you disclose your personal information to.
  10. **Updating your personal information**
    1. Should your personal information change or if you would like to review or delete your personal information you should do this directly on the Website through the registration section by following the easy steps below:
      1. click on " _my settings_";
      2. after you have clicked on " _my settings_ " you will see your personal information;
      3. update your personal information or click on " _delete my account_ " if you wish to delete your personal information.
    2. Please note that by deleting your account you will delete all your information and settings as well as clear any passwords. 
    3. Further to the above, you may contact as at [info@pamgolding.co.za](mailto:info@pamgolding.co.za) to correct or de-identify your personal information. Upon receipt of such request, we shall, as soon as is reasonably practicable:
      1. correct your personal information;
      2. de-identify your personal information;
      3. provide you with evidence in support of the personal information held by us; or
      4. where agreement cannot be reached, and if you so request, take such steps (as are reasonable in the circumstances) to attach your personal information, in such a manner that it will always be read with your personal information, an indication that a correction of your personal information has been requested but has not been made by us.
    4. We shall provide you with reasonable confirmation that the abovementioned actions (whichever may be applicable) have taken place. 
  11. **Consent**
    1. **By visiting our Website, you consent to us using your personal information as set out in this Privacy Policy**.
    2. PGP has a global reach. As such, there is a possibility that your personal information may have to be transferred to countries outside of South Africa. Insofar as your information may be transferred outside of South Africa, PGP shall take reasonable organisational and/or contractual measures to ensure that your personal information is processed by such third parties for the purposes for which it has been provided to us and that the required levels of protection have been implemented by such third parties to safeguard your personal information. **By using the Website and submitting your personal information to us, you consent to your personal information being transferred outside of South Africa.**
  12. **Opting out**
    1. Should you not wish to receive any marketing and promotional or other information from PGP, you may request PGP to cease sending you such information or request that your personal information be removed from our database or mailing list at any time. You will have the right to opt-out of receiving any communications from PGP by notifying PGP in writing.
  13. **Password and user name**
    1. It is your responsibility to choose a password and to keep it safe.
    2. You agree and warrant that your username and password shall: 
      1. be used for personal use only; and 
      2. not be disclosed by you to any third party. 
    3. For security purposes you agree to enter the correct username and password whenever accessing your account on the Website, failing which you will be denied access. 
    4. You agree that you will be granted access to the Website once the correct username and password have been entered, irrespective of whether the use of the username and password is unauthorised or fraudulent.  We cannot be held responsible for personal information being compromised due to a non-secure, disclosed or stolen password.
    5. You agree to notify PGP immediately upon becoming aware of or reasonably suspecting any unauthorised access to or use of your username and password and to take steps to mitigate any resultant loss or harm.
  14. **Amendment**
    1. We may change our Privacy Policy in our sole discretion and at any time without informing you thereof in writing. It is your responsibility to visit the Website periodically to review the Privacy Policy to which you are bound. If we change our Privacy Policy we will post the changes on the Website so that you may be aware of the personal information we collect and how we use it at all times. 
  15. **Contact us**
    1. All comments, questions, concerns or complaints regarding your personal information or this privacy policy, should be forwarded to us by using the contact details in the **Terms and Conditions**. ****
    2. The information officer for PGP is Meere Lemmer, Group Legal and Compliance Officer (Residential). ****
